Register of the Citizens Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Citizens Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government records
1949-1958
52007
Hoover Institution Archives
92 manuscript boxes, 1 motion picture film reel (38.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, newsletters, press releases, clippings, and printed matter, relating to the recommendations of the two Commissions on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government chaired by Herbert Hoover.
Citizens Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government
Access
Collection is stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To view films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/ to find the full extent of the collection.
Historical Note
The Citizens Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government (CCREBG) was organized in the state of New York in April 1949. It was established as a temporary, voluntary organization to follow through on the Hoover Report and to promote public and congressional support for the recommendations of the first Hoover Commission.
The Hoover Report was a popular reference made to the extensive studies made by the Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government under the direction of Herbert C. Hoover. The term "Hoover Report" quickly became a synonym for the investigation and constructive recommendations of the Commission. The first Hoover Commission established in 1947 when the U.S. Congress passed a law providing for a Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government. The commission was to aim at limiting expenditures, ensuring efficient performance, eliminating duplication, consolidating services, and defining and limiting executive functions. The second Hoover Commission was appointed under the Eisenhower administration. Its purpose was to contemplate changes in social and economic policy. Its right to issue subpoenas resulted in opposition by many government officials. In Hoover's estimate, Congress accepted about a third of the commission's proposals.
The membership of the CCREBG's Board of Directors consisted of agricultural, business, educational, labor, veterans and women's groups. In recognition of its essentially educational nature, the Bureau of Internal Revenue declared that contributions received by the Committee would be deductible for federal income tax purposes.
The CCREBG had two offices, one in New York City and another in Washington, D.C. A network of regional and state chairmen was created and held together by newsletters and periodic meetings. It provided speakers, film shows, editorials, resolutions, panels and forums, and radio and television announcements. The Committee developed 300 state and local affiliated committees with active outposts in every congressional district. "Little Hoover Commissions" were appointed in 28 state governments, as well as Hawaii and Alaska. The result was and unprecedented upsurge of public interest in government operations.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Citizens Committee for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government (CCREBG) cover the period of time from 1948 to 1958. During these years the CCREBG engaged in various operations to promote public and congressional support for the Hoover Commission's recommendations to streamline the federal government and curtail the waste of federal funds.
The records are divided into eight series. The first three (office file, correspondence, and reports) consist of materials issued and collected by the main administrative offices of the CCREBG. They include bulletins, circular letters, editorial analyses, memoranda, correspondence, minutes of meetings, press releases, and other materials. Included in the office file series are speeches and writings by officers of the CCREBG and others. The reports series contains reports issued by the CCREBG and includes reports by outside sources.
The Congressional legislation series provides complete sets congressional bills and their drafts, congressional hearing transcripts, reports, correspondence, and memoranda relating to legislation of the U.S. Congress on the recommendations of the Hoover Commission.
The reorganization plans series provides documentation on the various reorganization plans for the federal government by the Hoover Commission, and the State Committees series reflects the operations of the state committees and their relationship with the main office administration.
The subject file and printed matter series consist primarily of materials collected by the CCREBG, which relate to their operations in effecting reorganization of the Executive Branch of the government.
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; United States. Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (1947-1949); United States. Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (1953-1955); United States--Executive departments.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government.
- Office File, 1949-1957 (Box 1-12)
  Scope and Contents note
  Bulletins, circular and form letters, editorial analyses, handbooks, lists, memoranda, minutes of meetings, press releases, reports, speeches and writings, and other material. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General (Folder 1: 1-3)
  - Action kit (Folder 1: 4)
  - Award of Merit, 1952 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Bibliographies
    - General (Folder 1: 6)
    - Library of Congress (Folder 1: 7)
  - Biographical sketches of commissioners, staff members and consultants (Folder 1: 8)
  - Bulletins
    - Bull's-Eye Bulletin, 1956 (Folder 1: 9)
    - Information Bulletin
      - 1955-1956 (Folder 1: 10)
      - 1956 (Folder 1: 11)
      - 1957 (Folder 1: 12)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Reorganization News
      - 1949-1953 (Folder 2: 2)
      - 1955-1958 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Reorganization Record, 1949-1950 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Special Research Memorandum
      - 1953-1956 (Folder 2: 5)
      - 1957 (Folder 2: 6)
    - Washington Watchdog
      - 1950-1951 (Folder 2: 7)
      - 1952 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Circular letters, 1950-1952 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Citation of Achievement, 1951 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Congressional kit (Folder 2: 11)
  - Editorial analyses, 1955 (Folder 2: 12-13)
  - Financial appeals, 1951 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Form letters
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 3: 2-3)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Handbooks
    - Chairman's handbook (Folder 3: 5)
    - Revised Speaker's handbook (Folder 3: 6)
    - Speaker's handbook, 1949 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Instructions on organization, 1949 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Legislative program for 1951 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Letters from and to President Eisenhower, former President Herbert C. Hoover and the Citizens Committee, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Lists
    - Board of Directors (Folder 4: 2)
    - Chairmen and Executive Secretaries (Folder 4: 3)
    - Membership, 1949 May (Folder 4: 4)
    - National Committee members from California, 1949 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Press representatives (Folder 4: 6)
    - Prices for publications (Folder 4: 7)
  - Membership card, 1951 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1953 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Organization charts
    - Citizens Committee for the Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government (CCREBG) (Folder 4: 10)
    - Executive Branch of the Government (Folder 4: 11)
    - Federal Executive Departments and Agencies (Folder 4: 12-14)
  - Postage stamps issued by the CCREBG (Folder 4: 15)
  - Press releases
    - 1949
      - February-October (Folder 4: 16)
      - May-December (Folder 4: 17)
    - 1950 (Box 5)
      - January-May (Folder 5: 1)
      - April-May (Folder 5: 2)
      - June-July (Folder 5: 3-4)
      - July-December (Folder 5: 5)
      - August-December (Folder 5: 6)
    - 1951
      - January-March (Folder 5: 7)
      - January-September (Folder 5: 8)
      - March-April (Box-folder 6: 1)
      - May-October (Folder 6: 2)
      - October-December (Folder 6: 3)
    - 1952
      - January-April (Folder 6: 4)
      - January-June (Folder 6: 5)
      - May-July (Folder 6: 6)
      - June 3 (Folder 6: 7)
    - 1953-1954 (Folder 6: 8)
    - 1955 (Folder 6: 9)
    - 1956 (Folder 6: 10)
    - 1957 (Folder 6: 11)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Program kit (Folder 7: 2)
  - Resolutions
    - General. (Folder 7: 3)
      Includes samples
    - House Republican Conference, 1949 June 20 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Responses to questionnaires by members of Congress, 1950 (Folder 7: 5-6)
  - Rosters (Folder 7: 7)
  - Special memorandum, "Round Robin,", 1949-1952 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Speeches
    - Members of the CCREBG (Folder 7: 9)
    - Non-members (Folder 7: 10)
  - Statements by members of the CCREBG (Folder 7: 11)
  - Subject file
    - Action appeals, 1955-1956 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Board of Directors and Advisory Board (Folder 7: 13)
    - Briefing Session, 1957 June (Folder 8: 1-2)
    - Conferences
      - General
        - New York, 1949
          - October 12 (Folder 8: 3)
          - December 1 (Folder 8: 4)
        - New York, 1950 September 25-27 (Folder 8: 5)
        - New York City, 1951 October 24 (Folder 8: 6)
        - White Sulphur Springs (Greenbrier), 1951 October 6 (Folder 8: 7)
      - 2nd National Reorganization, Washington, D.C., 1952 February 18 (Folder 8: 8)
      - 3rd National Reorganization Conference, 1957 February 4-5 (Folder 8: 9-10)
      - 3rd National Reorganization Conference, 1957 February 4-5 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
      - Jaycee Conferences, 1958 May 19-21 (Folder 9: 3)
      - National Action Conference, Washington, D.C., 1956 March 15 (Folder 9: 4)
      - National Reorganization, Washington, D.C., 1949 December 12-13 (Folder 9: 5)
      - Teapot Tempest, 1958 March 8 (Folder 9: 6)
      - Western Regional, Salt Lake City, Utah, 1951 December 7 (Folder 9: 7)
    - Democratic Party (Folder 9: 8)
    - Examples of government fiscal inefficiency (Box-folder 10: 1-3)
    - Film strip, 1954 (Folder 10: 4)
    - Film strip kit (Folder 10: 5)
    - Fundraising
      - General (Folder 10: 6-7)
      - Climax Drive, 1957 (Folder 10: 8)
    - Hoover, Herbert. Interview with Lowell Thomas on Kinescope (Folder 10: 9)
    - Implementation of recommendations, 1955-1956 (Folder 10: 10)
    - Legislative goals (Folder 10: 11)
    - Meetings (Box 11)
      - 1953 December 15 (Folder 11: 1)
      - 1955-1956 (Folder 11: 2)
      - 1957 October 17 (Folder 11: 3)
    - National Reorganization Crusade, 1950 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Presidential Convention, 1952 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Reactions to the Commission's work, Congressional Record, 1955 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Recommendations (Folder 11: 7)
    - Reorganization Program, 1951 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Resolutions (Folder 11: 9)
    - School and Universities Committee (Folder 11: 10-11)
    - Speaker's Bureau (Folder 11: 12)
    - Special Committees (Folder 11: 13)
    - Spectaclathon (television program), 1956 (Folder 11: 14)
    - State Hoover Commissions (Folder 11: 15)
    - Subsidies (Folder 11: 16)
    - Symposium, 1951 (Folder 11: 17)
    - United States. Junior Chamber of Commerce (Folder 11: 18)
    - Washington Workshop, 1958 March-April (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
    - Waste Not, Want Not (documentary film), 1956 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Suggested letters, forms, and resolutions kit (Folder 12: 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 12: 6)
- Correspondence, 1949-1958 (Box 12-33)
  Correspondence arranged Alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General
    - General
      - General
        - 1949-1950 (Folder 12: 7)
        - 1956-1958 (Folder 12: 8-9)
        - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
      - Agency replies, 1952 (Folder 13: 3)
      - Answers to Robert Johnson's letter to agency head, 1950 September (Folder 13: 4)
      - Congressional comments regarding the reorganization of the Executive Branch of the government, 1949-1951 (Folder 13: 5)
      - Congressional requests, 1949 (Folder 13: 6)
      - Replies to Leadership Awards, 1952 (Folder 13: 7)
    - A (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
    - B (Folder 14: 4-6)
    - B (Box-folder 15: 1-3)
    - Ba-Be (Folder 15: 4)
    - Bi-By (Folder 15: 5)
    - C (Folder 15: 6)
    - C (Box-folder 16: 1-5)
    - D (Folder 16: 6)
    - D (Box-folder 17: 1-3)
    - E (Folder 17: 4-5)
    - F (Folder 17: 6)
    - F (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
    - G (Folder 18: 3-5)
    - H (Folder 18: 6)
    - H (Box-folder 19: 1-3)
    - Ha-Hi (Folder 19: 4)
    - Ho-Hu (Folder 19: 5)
    - I (Folder 19: 6)
    - J (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
    - K (Folder 20: 3-5)
    - L (Folder 20: 6)
    - L (Box-folder 21: 1-4)
    - M (Folder 21: 5-6)
    - M (Folder 22: 1-4)
    - Mc (Folder 22: 5-6)
    - Me-Mz (Folder 22: 7)
    - N (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
    - O (Folder 23: 3)
    - P (Folder 23: 4-6)
    - Q (Folder 23: 7)
    - R (Box-folder 24: 1-4)
    - S (Folder 24: 5)
    - S (Box-folder 25: 1-5)
    - S (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Sa-Sn (Folder 26: 2)
    - So-Sz (Folder 26: 3)
    - T (Folder 26: 4-6)
    - U (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - V (Folder 27: 2)
    - W (Folder 27: 3-6)
    - X-Z (Folder 27: 7)
  - Adams, Sherman, 1956 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Alvord and Alvord, 1949-1950 (Folder 27: 9)
  - American Forestry Association, 1949 (Folder 27: 10)
  - American Medical Association, 1949-1950 (Folder 27: 11)
  - Basic Refractories, Inc., 1955-1956 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Brown, Gordon C., 1958 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Burns, Louis J., 1957 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Calhoun, Leonard J., 1957-1958 (Folder 28: 4)
  - Castle, William R., 1949-1950 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the U.S.A., 1949-1952 (Folder 28: 6)
  - Coates, Charles, 1956-1957 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Council of State Governments, 1949-1950 (Folder 28: 8)
  - Covell, Joseph, 1950 (Folder 28: 9)
  - Dawson, William L., 1952 (Folder 28: 10)
  - Doherty, William H., 1957 (Folder 28: 11)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1954 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Fairman, Milton, 1955-1956 (Folder 28: 13)
  - Fountain, Irene, 1952-1953 (Folder 28: 14)
  - Francis, Clarence
    - 1955 (Folder 28: 15)
    - 1956 (Folder 28: 16)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - 1958 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Hancock, Harvey, 1957 (Folder 29: 3)
  - Heller, Ralph W., 1951 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Highsmith, Albert W., 1956-1958 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Hook, Charles, 1954-1956 (Folder 29: 6)
  - Hoover, Eleanor
    - 1955 (Folder 29: 7)
    - 1956 (Folder 29: 8)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 29: 9)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. (Box 30)
    - 1953-1955 (Folder 30: 1)
    - 1956 (Folder 30: 2)
    - 1957 (Folder 30: 3)
    - 1958 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Izaak Walton League, 1949 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Johnson, Robert L., 1949-1951 (Folder 30: 6)
  - Kestnbaum, Meyer, 1955-1958 (Folder 30: 7)
  - Leva, Marx, 1951-1952 (Folder 30: 8)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1949 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Luidens, Joy M., 1958 (Folder 30: 10)
  - MacNeil, Neil, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Merson, Martin
    - 1950 (Folder 31: 2)
    - 1951 (Folder 31: 3-4)
    - 1952 (Folder 31: 5)
  - Metz, Harold W.
    - 1955-1956 (Folder 31: 6)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 32: 1-2)
  - Metz, Kay, 1957-1958 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Minority Policy Committee, 1949-1952 (Folder 32: 4)
  - Mitchell, Sidney A., 1950-1954 (Folder 32: 5)
  - Morgan, Gerald, 1949-1952 (Folder 32: 6)
  - O'Rourke, John T., 1949 (Folder 32: 7)
  - Paramount News, 1949 (Folder 32: 8)
  - Roberts, A. B., 1949 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Sherman, Edward A., 1957 (Folder 32: 10)
  - Shoemaker, Perry M., 1957-1958 (Folder 32: 11)
  - Society for the Advancement of Management, 1949 (Folder 32: 12)
  - Tamblyn, George O., 1957-1958 (Folder 32: 13)
  - Tax Foundation, 1949-1950 (Folder 32: 14)
  - Transportation Association of America, 1951-1952 (Folder 32: 15)
  - Trumble, Eugene F., 1955-1956 (Folder 32: 16)
  - United States. Bureau of the Budget
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 32: 17)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - United States. Congress.
    - House of Representatives. Committee on Expenditures in the Executive Departments, 1949-1951 (Folder 33: 2)
    - Senate. Committee on Expenditures in the Executive Departments, 1949-1951 (Folder 33: 3)
  - United States. Department of Commerce
    - General, 1952 (Folder 33: 4)
    - Civil Aeronautics Board, 1952 (Folder 33: 5)
    - Federal Communications Commission, 1952 (Folder 33: 6)
    - Federal Power Commission, 1952 (Folder 33: 7)
    - Federal Trade Commission, 1952 (Folder 33: 8)
    - Indian Claims Commission, 1952 (Folder 33: 9)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1952 (Folder 33: 10)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics, 1952 (Folder 33: 11)
    - National Labor Relations Board, 1949-1952 (Folder 33: 12)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1952 (Folder 33: 13)
  - United States. Department of Labor, 1952-1953 (Folder 33: 14)
  - United States. Department of the Interior, 1952-1953 (Folder 33: 15)
  - United States. Department of the Treasury, 1952-1953 (Folder 33: 16)
  - United States. Junior Chamber of Commerce (Jaycees)
    - 1950 (Folder 33: 17)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 33: 18)
  - Upman, Frank, 1957 (Folder 33: 19)
  - Van Rensselaer, Bernard, 1957 (Folder 33: 20)
  - Voorhees, Tracy S., 1955-1956 (Folder 33: 21)
  - Weck, Egon E., 1957 (Folder 33: 22)
  - Widener, Mary, 1955 (Folder 33: 23)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence
    - Organizations, 1949-1954 (Folder 33: 24)
    - Vice Chairmen, 1953 (Folder 33: 25)
- Reports, 1948-1956 (Box 34-43)
  Reports issued by the CCREBG and other agencies. Arranged alphabetically by name of agency and therein by title of report
  - Issued by the CCREBG
    - General (Folder 34: 1-2)
    - "Activities Report - First Six Months of 1954,", 1954 July 28 (Folder 34: 3)
    - "Analysis of Previous Proposals for Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government,", 1948 September 24 (Folder 34: 4)
    - "Better Government at a Better Price,", n.d. (Folder 34: 5)
    - "The Central Administration Organization for the Territories and Dependencies of the U.S.,", 1948 October 16 (Folder 34: 6)
    - "Citizens Committee Operating Plans - Second Half 1954," (Folder 34: 7)
    - "Departmental Management by Agency,", n.d. (Folder 34: 8)
    - "Departmental Management by Agency,", n.d. (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - "The Division of Estimates of the Bureau of the Budget,", n.d. (Folder 35: 2)
    - "Final Report,", 1955-1956 (Folder 35: 3)
    - "Kestbaum Report"
      - 1956 October (Folder 35: 4)
      - 1958 February (Folder 35: 5)
    - "Progress Report,", 1956 (Folder 35: 6)
    - "Report on Activities," Greater NY Citizens Committee for the Hoover Report,", 1950 December 30 (Folder 35: 7)
    - "Semi-Annual Report on Activities,", 1954 June (Folder 35: 8)
    - "Status of the Hoover Report"
      - 1953 November (Folder 35: 9)
      - 1955 (Folder 36: 1)
  - Issued by CCREBG committees
    - Committee on Federal Medical Services, 1948 November
      - "Area Surveys of the Subcommittee on Hospitalization" (Folder 36: 2)
      - "Federal Health Activities and Programs" (Folder 36: 3)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Armed Forces Hospitalization" (Folder 36: 4)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Hospitalization" (Folder 36: 5)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Medical Manpower" (Folder 36: 6)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Medical Supply" (Folder 36: 7)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Preventive Medicine and Public Health" (Folder 36: 8)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Psychiatry and Neurology" (Folder 36: 9)
      - "Report of the Subcommittee on Tuberculosis" (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - Committee on Federal State Relations, "Report to the Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government,", 1948 September 28 (Folder 37: 2)
    - Committee on Independent Regulatory Commissions, 1948
      - "Staff Report on the Civil Aeronautics Board,", November (Folder 37: 3)
      - "Staff Report on the Federal Communications Commission,", September 15 (Folder 37: 4)
      - "Staff Report on the Federal Power Commission,", October (Folder 37: 5)
      - "Staff Report on the Federal Reserve System,", November (Box-folder 38: 1)
      - "Staff Report on the Federal Trade Commission,", September (Folder 38: 2)
      - "Staff Report on the Interstate Commerce Commission,", November (Folder 38: 3)
      - "Staff Report on the National Labor Relations Board,", August (Folder 38: 4)
      - "Staff Report on the Securities and Exchange Commission,", November (Folder 38: 5)
      - "Staff Report on the U.S. Maritime Commission,", November (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Committee on Indian Affairs, "Report to the Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government,", 1948 October (Folder 39: 2-3)
    - Committee on the National Security Organization, "Report to the CCREBG,", 1948 November 15
      - Volume I (Folder 39: 4)
      - Volume II (Folder 39: 5)
    - Committee on the National Security Organization, "Report to the CCREBG,", 1948 November 15
      - Volume III (Folder 40: 1)
      - Volume IV (Folder 40: 2)
    - Committee on Natural Resources, "A Report to the Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government,", 1948 September 1 (Folder 40: 3)
    - Committee on Veterans Affairs, "Report to the Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government,", n.d. (Folder 40: 4)
    - Fiscal Budgeting and Accounting Task Force, Accounting Policy Committee, "Report on the Accounting Needs of the Federal Government," (Folder 40: 5)
    - Personnel Policy Committee, "Report,", 1948 October (Folder 40: 6)
    - Public Task Force, "Report to the CCREBG,", 1948 October 21 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Issued by government agencies and organizations
    - Federal Government Field Services, 1948
      - "Report to the Commission of the Executive Branch of the Government,", October (Folder 41: 2)
      - "A Survey for the Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government,", October 28 (Folder 41: 3)
    - Federal Supply Project, "Detailed Report on the Federal Supply System,", 1948 September (Folder 41: 4-5)
    - Federal Supply Project, "Detailed Report on the Federal Supply System,", 1948 September (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - United States. Bureau of the Budget, "The Legislative Clearance Function in the Bureau of the Budget,", 1948 September 6 (Folder 42: 2)
    - United States. Price Stabilization Office, "The Hoover Commission Recommendations and the Office of Price Stabilization,", 1951 October (Folder 42: 3)
  - Issued by various organizations
    - General
      - "The Military Budget,", n.d. (Folder 42: 4)
      - "Report of the Air Force on Recommendations of the Hoover Commission,", 1952 July 11 (Folder 42: 5)
      - "Report of the Department of the Army on Recommendations of the Hoover Commission,", 1952 July 29 (Folder 42: 6)
      - "Report of the Department of the Navy on Recommendations of the Hoover Commission,", 1952 July 28 (Folder 42: 7)
    - Brookings Institution
      - "Functions and Activities of the National Government in the Field of Welfare,", 1948 December (Folder 42: 8)
      - "Report to the Commission on Transportation and the National Government,", 1948 October
        - Volume I (Folder 42: 9)
        - Volume II (Folder 42: 10-11)
        - Volume II (Box-folder 43: 1)